<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A letter from His Excellency Sir Thomas Fairfax, in answer to the petition of the eleven members, and the votes of the House, for bringing in a particular charge against them. An order by His Excellency, for appointing a committee of the army to hold a treaty with the commissioners of Parliament. And a proclamation by His Excellency, forbidding any abuse or obstruction to the levying the excize or other assessments. By the appointment of his Excellency Sir Tho: Fairfax, and the Councel of war. Wickam, July 1. 1647. Signed John Rushworth.</title>
            <author>Fairfax, Thomas Fairfax, Baron, 1612-1671.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1647</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A84767</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F174</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E396_23</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R201659</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99862159</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99862159</idno>
            <idno type="VID">160354</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A84767)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 160354)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 63:E396[23])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A letter from His Excellency Sir Thomas Fairfax, in answer to the petition of the eleven members, and the votes of the House, for bringing in a particular charge against them. An order by His Excellency, for appointing a committee of the army to hold a treaty with the commissioners of Parliament. And a proclamation by His Excellency, forbidding any abuse or obstruction to the levying the excize or other assessments. By the appointment of his Excellency Sir Tho: Fairfax, and the Councel of war. Wickam, July 1. 1647. Signed John Rushworth.</title>
                  <author>Fairfax, Thomas Fairfax, Baron, 1612-1671.</author>
                  <author>England and Wales. Army. Council.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>7, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Laurence Chapman,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London: :</pubPlace>
                  <date>July 5. 1547, [i.e. 1647]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Parliament --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>England and Wales. --  Parliament. --  House of Commons --  Expulsion --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Impeachment --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Treaties --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:160354:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A LETTER FROM His Excellency Sir <hi>Thomas Fairfax,</hi> In Anſwer to the <hi>Petition</hi> of the Eleven Members, and the <hi>Votes</hi> of the Houſe, for bringing in a particular Charge againſt them.</p>
            <p>An ORDER by His Excellency, for appointing a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee of the Army to hold a Treaty with the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners of PARLIAMENT.</p>
            <p>AND A PROCLAMATION By His EXCELLENCY, Forbidding any Abuſe or Obſtruction to the Levying the Excize or other Aſſeſſments.</p>
            <p>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license">
                        <p>BY the appointment of his Excellency Sir <hi>Tho: Fairfax,</hi> and the Councel of War.</p>
                        <closer>
                           <dateline>Wickam, <date>July 1. 1647.</date>
                           </dateline>
                           <signed>Signed JOHN RUSHWORTH.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed for <hi>Laurence Chapman,</hi> JULY 5. 1547,</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:160354:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:160354:2"/>
            <head>A PROCLAMATION From His Excellency Sir <hi>THOMAS FAIRFAX,</hi> Forbidding any abuſe or obſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction to be offered to any Officers of the Parliament, in levying Exciſe or other Aſſeſſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hereas it hath pleaſed the Hono<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable Houſe of Commons, by their Order of the 28 of June laſt paſt to recommend unto me. That an effectual courſe may be taken, that no diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couragement or obſtruction may be given by the Soldiers, to the due levying and bringing in the Exciſe, and other Aſſeſſments and pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments to the Parliament: And to the end that ſuch Obſtruction may be prevented,
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:160354:3"/>I do hereby require all Officers and Soldiers of the Army under my Command, That they do not in any kinde diſcourage or ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruct the due levying and bringing in of the Exciſe, and other Aſſeſſments and payments to the Parliament: And if any Officer or Soldier ſhall notwithſtanding go about to hinder or obſtruct the ſame, I do hereby re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire the Officer commanding in chief, at preſent the Troop, Company or Regiment in thoſe parts where ſuch obſtruction ſhall be given, to ſend the Officers or Soldiers ſo offending in cuſtody to the Head-quarter, That they may be proceeded againſt for the contempt of this Order: And in caſe of any tumultuous carriage by any perſons, tending to the obſtructing the due levying of Excize and payments as aforeſaid, the ſaid Officers and Soldiers are to be aiding and aſsiſting for the ſuppreſsing of the ſame.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given under my Hand and Seal at <hi>Wickham</hi> 
                  <date>the Firſt day of July, 1647.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>Tho: Fairfax.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="order_for_treating_with_Parliament">
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:160354:3"/>
            <head>
               <date>Thurſday, July 1.</date> His Excellency ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed theſe Officers of the Army to Treat.</head>
            <p>I Do hereby appoint Lieutenant General <hi>Cromwel,</hi> Commiſſary General <hi>Ireton,</hi> Colonel <hi>Fleetwood,</hi> Colonel <hi>Rainsborough,</hi> and Colonel <hi>Harriſon,</hi> Colo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nel Sir <hi>Hardres Waller,</hi> Colonel <hi>Rich,</hi> Colonel <hi>Lam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bert,</hi> Colonel <hi>Hamond,</hi> and Major <hi>Disborough;</hi> Theſe ten or any five of them (of which the major part to be of the five laſt) to Treat and Debate with the Right Honorable, The Commiſſioners of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment reſiding with the Army, upon the Papers and Deſires ſent from the Army to both Houſes, and the Votes ſent to the Army, according to the effect of the Order of both Houſes, dated the 26 of June, 1647. And for that purpoſe to attend the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners at their lodging at the Katherine wheel to morrow morning by eight of the clock, and ſo from time to time, and place to place as ſhall be mutually agreed on.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given under my Hand and Seal at <hi>Wick<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham,</hi> 
                  <date>the firſt day of July, 1647.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>T: Fairfax.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="letter">
            <pb n="6" facs="tcp:160354:4"/>
            <head>To the Right Honorable, The Commiſsioners of Parliament now reſiding with the Army.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>My Lords and Gentlemen,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>HAving with my Councel of War con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſidered of the Votes of the Houſe of Commons of the 29 of June, 1647. which you ſent me, for the bringing in the particu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar Charge and proofs againſt the Members charged by the Army, by Friday next at far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>theſt: As I finde a great willingneſs in them to anſwer the expectation of the Houſe in all things, ſo in this particular; but the things being of that importance to the Kingdom, and the perſons charged ſo many in number, hath taken up more time then was expected; We deſire therefore, That it may be reſpited until Tueſday next, at which time we ſhall
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:160354:4"/>fail to bring it in; although we could wiſh that no time might be loſt therein which might be improved for the preſent ſettlement of the Affairs of this Kingdom, and that the Kingdom ſhall then ſee, we have not impea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ched the Gentlemen out of any private re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpects, but in affection and duty to the Pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lique. I remain</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Wickam, <date>July 1. 1647.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>Your very affectionate Friend and Servant, <hi>Tho: Fairfax.</hi>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
